<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Mykyta&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Mykyta&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, Mykyta Myronenko.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Toolbox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-toolbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-toolbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a little post about what software and hardware I use when working on my little films. I&amp;rsquo;m always curious to know what other people are using, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share, even if only to have this as an inventory list for myself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to note, that to start with making things it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary to go out and buy expensive tools (or the tools listed below). Best policy is to use what you already have, and expand your toolbelt slowly, when necessary, and when affordable. Most things I own I got second-hand or for free.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treat film like painting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/treat-film-like-painting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/treat-film-like-painting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’d ever painted or sculpted, good practical advice is to work on all the little bits for the piece in parallel. You start with lower detail, get the big moves figured out, and while maintaining a consistent resolution of your strokes (or chips? do scultpors chip?), you iteratively progress into a more detailed version. ^metaphor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like this because you can take as much time, or be as loose as you want, and call it done whenever. A master’s painting looks good at any point of its completion. A mural may be the finished accomplished vision of the artist, and a sketch is also; what matters is intent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did online content kill TV sketch come</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/did-online-content-kill-tv-sketch-comedy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/did-online-content-kill-tv-sketch-comedy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[!summary] For context:&#xA;Originally I wrote this as a comment under Tomska’s “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hrEv7gLKoo8&#34;&gt;Who Killed Comedy?&lt;/a&gt;”, but thought it’d be worth sharing here too. The super short video summary is: &lt;em&gt;with the rise of social media, and Internet video comedy on sites like YouTube and TikTok, we have killed off TV sketch comedy, meaning there might come a time when we will never have the likes of Key &amp;amp; Peele, or Monty Python to enrich our cultural zeitgest&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astranaut Concept Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/astronaut-concept-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/astronaut-concept-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/scl/fi/829zsyllfsi55v0maticz/astranaut-concept-art.png?rlkey=dsv6fraa98clpulnf3g4zd9ij&amp;amp;st=kjkdzo94&amp;amp;raw=1&#34; alt=&#34;Concept Art of a Spaceman for my animation, made in Blender.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Related: [[stuck floating animation project]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I learned modelling in Blender for the first time.md</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-i-learned-modelling-in-blender-for-the-first-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/what-i-learned-modelling-in-blender-for-the-first-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the film I’m currently working on (working title: &lt;em&gt;[[stuck floating animation project|stuck floating]]&lt;/em&gt;) I’ve decided that the best aesthetic is hybrid animation, combining 3D and 2D techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I launched blender and for the past week have been learning the ins-and-outs. By now I have a basic grasp on how to box model.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;box-modelling&#34;&gt;Box modelling&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s a technique used in 3D modelling where you start with a basic object, like a cube, and shape it into a more complex model. In Blender you’d do it by subdividing faces and edges, knife-cutting planes, adding ridges, extruding parts or moving vertices around - move, rotate and scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I will give film making my best shot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-give-film-making-my-best-shot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/i-will-give-film-making-my-best-shot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been a while that something has excited me as much as the idea of independent film making. With all the free tools we have at our disposal, and the online platforms for video distribution, combined with risk-averse stagnating traditional cinema, I can’t shake the feeling that we are in a golden age of independent film making.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think part of my own (misplaced) self-confidence comes from the fact that I have always had many interests. I’ve always wanted to dip my toes in all aspects of art, and I growing with platforms like YouTube I saw how people who are brave, hard-working, and with something to share find their own place to connect with other creators and audiences. A part of me thinks “I could do that”, but another part says “you will fail”, and I think both are right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too anxious to create</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/too-anxious-to-create/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/too-anxious-to-create/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For over a year I’ve had an itch, a desire at the back of my throat to make things. When I sit down and just start, the nagging thoughts fade away and I become immersed in the process. It’s enjoyable, it is what gives me total freedom, a healthy escape. And being consistently creative is what seems to coincide with “the upswing periods”&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in my life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only thing that has been stopping me is this cowardly voice in the back of my head. It quickly and almost totally fades away once I start, but in the moments of anticipation, before sit down and make, it’s the loudest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working on my first films with zero skills</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/working-on-my-first-films-with-zero-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/working-on-my-first-films-with-zero-skills/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the films I am currently working on requires 3D animation,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; the bad news is that I have nearly zero experience with this. I am very good with CAD 3D modelling, but that’s different from what is necessary for film animation. I’ve made the donut 5 years ago&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but most of what I’d learned has been forgotten. In essence, for this project I need to re-learn Blender.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Specifically I will need to learn from scratch:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of the Faceless, the Generic, and the Mundane - Examination of late Soviet Modernist mass housing in context of Moscow Demolitions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-defence-of-faceless-and-mundane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-defence-of-faceless-and-mundane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Socialist architecture, in particular the industrialised mass housing, has recently become the subject of various concerns, debates and interventions, which spark social reactions and inspire the countless newspaper headlines. The contradictory, but unique phenomenon of Soviet social housing appears to have infinite potential for dividing people on political, aesthetic and emotional basis. USSR architecture, seen by many as a symbol of both the suppression, and dejection of individualism, had also took on the responsibility of fulfilling a colossal social role, settling tens of millions families with &lt;em&gt;their own&lt;/em&gt; apartments. Monolithic, massive in scale yet after decades of sub-par maintenance and far past their expiration date these concrete giants are now ephemeral in their mode of existence. The endangered world, full of stories, myths and secrets, heroes and villains, encompassed within the modular panelled walls of these residences, still plays an important social role as housing for the dissonant collective memory and culture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
